

Andrash Yang

Full-Stack Web Developer

Nationality: Taiwanese
Fluent in both written and spoken
English

My Portfolio:

https://andrash.dev/
My GitHub:

https://github.com/cocoychris

I am an engineer who was born and forged on a battlefield. I picked up guns and started shooting before I had any formal training or even knew how to aim and shoot properly. I shot myself over and over again with my own gun and eventually figured out how to do it right on my own. This is how I started my software engineering journey at the age of 14.

20 years later, I am a very experienced software architect who still loves to code and is even more obsessed with elegant software architecture. OOP and SOA are my favorites and I use them all the time with different languages.

I am a full-stack software engineer, former mobile app developer and indie game developer. I design my own algorithms and 2D game engines because I enjoy it. I am not afraid to learn new things or face new challenges and even enjoy them like a new puzzle game.

TypeScript, Node.js, NestJS, React.js, PostgreSQL and Docker are my familiar tech stack and I am always excited to learn something new.

Currently, I am looking for a work environment where my creativity and obsession for clean, maintainable code is appreciated. (Checkout my coding style)

Familiar Tech Stack and Skills

Frontend	Backend	Auth & Security
 React.js (7/10) JQuery RWD using CSS Material UI Vite (Webpack replacement) SVG Animation 	 TypeScript (8/10) Node.js (9/10) Nest.js (7/10) or without Express.js (8/10) REST API design Socket.io EJS for SSR 	 Passport.js Cookie-based session JWT implementation CORS setup CSRF prevention Password encryption Zod data validation
Database	Dev & Deployment Tools	Others
 Database design and operation using: PostgreSQL Prisma ORM Drizzle ORM 	 Docker (6/10) Swagger, JSDoc and TypeDoc Ubuntu & Nginx Jest unit testing Git & GitHub 	 OOP design pattern (8/10) SOA design pattern Web scraping with Puppeteer Custom algorithm for games & business logic

Featured Full-Stack Projects



HiGo Shared Electric Scooter (Recent Project)

Developed a robust backend system for a shared electric scooter rental service in Kaohsiung City, Taiwan. Implemented core business logic, schema and REST APIs to power both mobile apps (<u>Android</u>, <u>iOS</u>) and management portal (private website). Key features included vehicle/area/order/payment/user/manager management module and real-time location tracking & remote control function.



Playground by Andrash

A gamified portfolio. Offers you a unique, game-like web experience with a **real-time multiplayer world** built from scratch using **Socket.io**, **React** and **Node** without using any existing game engine/framework.

Simply invite friends and explore together as your character avatars move in sync! There is even a **map editor** for you to create your own custom worlds. In addition, the **RWD design** makes it easy to access on both desktop and mobile environments.

Learn More

- The website: https://andrash.dev/
- Introduction Article: https://andrash.dev/page/md/about this place



Automated Robot Platform

A Robotic Process Automation (RPA) system to automate repetitive tasks. This platform includes a **web interface for managing and monitoring bot processes**, enabling scheduling, queuing, and real-time tracking. Additionally, a powerful **scripting API** empowers bot builders to automate complex actions across web and desktop applications. These actions include SFTP operations, email sending, file downloads, and simulated keyboard input.

Learn More

- Demo Video on YouTube:
 https://youtu.be/IO3-2 hz4XU
- Introduction Article:
 https://andrash.dev/page/md/project_arp_system
 m

Education

Earned a bachelor's degree in philosophy from Chinese Culture University, graduating early with honors in 2012. Self-taught in programming and web development since 2003 while in high school, motivated by the dream of making my own computer game (with Macromedia/Adobe Flash).

Work Experience



Backend Developer Handy Tech Ltd. (Cambrian soft) 08/2024 - Now Tainan, Taiwan

Worked on the HiGo Shared Electric Scooter project as the primary backend developer, responsible for creating the core business logic (NestJS), database schema (PostgreSQL, Prisma), REST API (Express), document (Swagger), and project deployment (Docker).



Information System Senior Executive **BRANDS** BRAND'S SUNTORY LTD. TAIWAN BRANCH (MALAYSIA) 08/2019 - 02/2023 Taipei, Taiwan

- Designed and developed the ARP (Automated Robot Platform) system used by Finance, Marketing, Sales and Legal departments for over 2 years.
- Coordinator of an international (Japan & India) outsourcing project (sales report generation system).



Mobile App Engineer QLL (Quick Language Learning) Pte. 01/2015 - 02/2016

Taipei, Taiwan

- Developed 3+ cross-platform mobile apps using Corona SDK (Solar 2D) and Lua. Responsible for building the company's core product (QLand App, an interactive ebook reader for language learning).
- Built a **UI component library** and an **OOP library** that turns Lua into an OOP language.
- Learn more: https://andrash.dev/page/md/mobile app dev



Computer Science & Coding Teacher (Part-time) Qing Shui High School

Taught computer science and coding (HTML, Lua, etc...) to high school students.



Mobile App Engineer Intern QLL (Quick Language Learning) Pte. 04/2012 - 02/2013

- Became familiar with the Corona SDK (Solar 2D) and Lua.
- Developed FBDraw, a painting app that comes with different brushes and allows users to post their paintings to their Facebook.



Indie game developer Freelance / Non-profit 09/2008 - 04/2012 Taipei, Taiwan

Taipei, Taiwan

- Created Flash games as a hobby and offered them for free while studying philosophy in college.
- Also worked as a freelance software developer, collaborating with my professor to create interactive software as the teaching material for his logic class.
- Game demo video: The Wedding Protector
- Game demo video: Car Chasing
- Learn more: https://andrash.dev/page/md/indie_game_development

- Start coding since 2003 -